
<!DOCTYPE HTML PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN">
<HTML>
	<HEAD>
		<title>Pennsylvania Spatial Data Access | Full Metadata</title>
		<meta name="GENERATOR" content="Microsoft Visual Studio.NET 7.0">
		<meta name="CODE_LANGUAGE" content="Visual Basic 7.0">
		<meta name="vs_defaultClientScript" content="JavaScript">
		<meta name="vs_targetSchema" content="http://schemas.microsoft.com/intellisense/ie5">
	    <link rel="shortcut icon" href="http://maps.pasda.psu.edu/Images/favicon.ico" type="image/x-icon" />
        <script>
          (function(i,s,o,g,r,a,m){i['GoogleAnalyticsObject']=r;i[r]=i[r]||function(){
          (i[r].q=i[r].q||[]).push(arguments)},i[r].l=1*new Date();a=s.createElement(o),
          m=s.getElementsByTagName(o)[0];a.async=1;a.src=g;m.parentNode.insertBefore(a,m)
          })(window,document,'script','//www.google-analytics.com/analytics.js','ga');

          ga('create', 'UA-41373351-5', 'psu.edu');
          ga('send', 'pageview');

        </script>
</HEAD>
	<body MS_POSITIONING="GridLayout">
		<form method="post" action="./FullMetadataDisplay.aspx?file=Pennsylvania_soil_metadata_201409.xml" id="Form1">
<input type="hidden" name="__VIEWSTATE" id="__VIEWSTATE" value="/wEPDwULLTEzNDA3MDMyNjVkZCi1cbXMhfZI+elmwl4oTersdOt9nxHHv5HGNLdvg2y4" />

<input type="hidden" name="__VIEWSTATEGENERATOR" id="__VIEWSTATEGENERATOR" value="D999016F" />
			<HTML>
  <HEAD>
    <META http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html; charset=utf-8">
    <SCRIPT type="text/javascript">

      function fix(e) {
        var par = e.parentNode;
        e.id = "";
        e.style.marginLeft = "0.42in";
        var pos = e.innerText.indexOf("\n");
        if (pos > 0) {
          while (pos > 0) {
            var t = e.childNodes(0);
            var n = document.createElement("PRE");
            var s = t.splitText(pos);
            e.insertAdjacentElement("afterEnd", n);
            n.appendChild(s);
            n.style.marginLeft = "0.42in";
            e = n;
            pos = e.innerText.indexOf("\n");
          }
          var count = (par.children.length);
          for (var i = 0; i < count; i++) {
            e = par.children(i);
            if (e.tagName == "PRE") {
              pos = e.innerText.indexOf(">");
              if (pos != 0) {
                n = document.createElement("DD");
                e.insertAdjacentElement("afterEnd", n);
                n.innerText = e.innerText;
                e.removeNode(true);
              }
            }
          }
          if (par.children.tags("PRE").length > 0) {
            count = (par.children.length);
            for (i = 0; i < count; i++) {
              e = par.children(i);
              if (e.tagName == "PRE") {
                e.id = "";
                if (i < (count-1)) {
                  var e2 = par.children(i + 1);
                  if (e2.tagName == "PRE") {
                    e.insertAdjacentText("beforeEnd", e2.innerText+"\n");
                    e2.removeNode(true);
                    count = count-1;
                    i = i-1;
                  }
                }
              }
            }
          }
        }
        else {
          n = document.createElement("DD");
          par.appendChild(n);
          n.innerText = e.innerText;
          e.removeNode(true);
        }
      }

    </SCRIPT>
  </HEAD>
  <BODY oncontextmenu="return true">
    <A name="Top">
    </A>
    <H2>Soil Survey Geographic (SSURGO) database for Pennsylvania</H2>
    <UL>
      <LI>
        <A HREF="#Identification_Information">Identification_Information</A>
      </LI>
      <LI>
        <A HREF="#Data_Quality_Information">Data_Quality_Information</A>
      </LI>
      <LI>
        <A HREF="#Spatial_Data_Organization_Information">Spatial_Data_Organization_Information</A>
      </LI>
      <LI>
        <A HREF="#Spatial_Reference_Information">Spatial_Reference_Information</A>
      </LI>
      <LI>
        <A HREF="#Entity_and_Attribute_Information">Entity_and_Attribute_Information</A>
      </LI>
      <LI>
        <A HREF="#EEA">
                  Distribution_Information 
                </A>
      </LI>
      <LI>
        <A HREF="#Metadata_Reference_Information">Metadata_Reference_Information</A>
      </LI>
    </UL>
    <A name="Identification_Information">
      <HR>
    </A>
    <DL>
      <DT>
        <I>Identification_Information:</I>
      </DT>
      <DD>
        <DL>
          <DT>
            <I>Citation:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Citation_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Originator:</I>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service
</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Publication_Date:</I>20140915</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Title:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>Soil Survey Geographic (SSURGO) database for Pennsylvania</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Publication_Information:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Publication_Place:</I>Fort Worth, Texas</DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Publisher:</I>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service
</DT>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Other_Citation_Details:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>pa001</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Online_Linkage:</I>
                    <A TARGET="viewer" HREF="http://websoilsurvey.nrcs.usda.gov">http://websoilsurvey.nrcs.usda.gov</A>
                  </DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Description:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DIV>
                <DT>
                  <I>Abstract:</I>
                </DT>
                <PRE>This data set is a digital soil survey and generally is the most detailed level of soil geographic data developed by the National Cooperative Soil Survey. The information was prepared by digitizing maps, by compiling information onto a planimetric correct base and digitizing, or by revising digitized maps using remotely sensed and other information. This data set consists of georeferenced digital map data and computerized attribute data. The map data are in a soil survey area extent format and include a detailed, field verified inventory of soils and miscellaneous areas that normally occur in a repeatable pattern on the landscape and that can be cartographically shown at the scale mapped. A special soil features layer (point and line features) is optional. This layer displays the location of features too small to delineate at the mapping scale, but they are large enough and contrasting enough to significantly influence use and management. The soil map units are linked to attributes in the National Soil Information System relational database, which gives the proportionate extent of the component soils and their properties.</PRE>
              </DIV>
              <DIV>
                <DT>
                  <I>Purpose:</I>
                </DT>
                <PRE>SSURGO depicts information about the kinds and distribution of soils on the landscape. The soil map and data used in the SSURGO product were prepared by soil scientists as part of the National Cooperative Soil Survey.</PRE>
              </DIV>
              <DIV>
                <DT>
                  <I>Supplemental_Information:</I>
                </DT>
                <PRE>
Digital versions of hydrography, cultural features, and other
associated layers that are not part of the SSURGO data set may be
available from the primary organization listed in the Point of
Contact.
</PRE>
              </DIV>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Time_Period_of_Content:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Time_Period_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Range_of_Dates/Times:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Beginning_Date:</I>19990415</DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Ending_Date:</I>20140915</DT>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DIV>
                <DT>
                  <I>Currentness_Reference:</I>
                </DT>
                <PRE>publication date</PRE>
              </DIV>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Status:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Progress:</I>Complete</DT>
              <DT>
                <I>Maintenance_and_Update_Frequency:</I>As needed</DT>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Spatial_Domain:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Bounding_Coordinates:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>West_Bounding_Coordinate:</I>-77.472</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>East_Bounding_Coordinate:</I>-76.955</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>North_Bounding_Coordinate:</I>40.070</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>South_Bounding_Coordinate:</I>39.720</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Keywords:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Theme:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Theme_Keyword_Thesaurus:</I>None</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Theme_Keyword:</I>soil survey</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Theme_Keyword:</I>soils</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Theme_Keyword:</I>Soil Survey Geographic</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Theme_Keyword:</I>SSURGO</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Place:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Place_Keyword_Thesaurus:</I>USGS Geographic Names Information System (GNIS)</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Place_Keyword:</I>Pennsylvania</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Access_Constraints:</I>None</DT>
          <DIV>
            <DT>
              <I>Use_Constraints:</I>
            </DT>
            <PRE>
The U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation
Service, should be acknowledged as the data source in products
derived from these data.

This data set is not designed for use as a primary regulatory tool
in permitting or citing decisions, but may be used as a reference
source. This is public information and may be interpreted by
organizations, agencies, units of government, or others based on
needs; however, they are responsible for the appropriate
application. Federal, State, or local regulatory bodies are not to
reassign to the Natural Resources Conservation Service any
authority for the decisions that they make. The Natural Resources
Conservation Service will not perform any evaluations of these maps
for purposes related solely to State or local regulatory programs.

Photographic or digital enlargement of these maps to scales greater
than at which they were originally mapped can cause misinterpretation
of the data. If enlarged, maps do not show the small areas of
contrasting soils that could have been shown at a larger scale. The
depicted soil boundaries, interpretations, and analysis derived from
them do not eliminate the need for onsite sampling, testing, and
detailed study of specific sites for intensive uses. Thus, these data
and their interpretations are intended for planning purposes only.
Digital data files are periodically updated. Files are dated, and
users are responsible for obtaining the latest version of the data.
</PRE>
          </DIV>
          <DT>
            <I>Point_of_Contact:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Contact_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Organization_Primary:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Contact_Organization:</I>U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation Service</DT>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Position:</I>State Soil Scientist</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Address:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Address_Type:</I>mailing address</DT>
                      <DIV>
                        <DT>
                          <I>Address:</I>
                        </DT>
                        <PRE>USDA-NRCS</PRE>
                      </DIV>
                      <DIV>
                        <DT>
                          <I>Address:</I>
                        </DT>
                        <PRE>One Credit Union Place, Suite 340</PRE>
                      </DIV>
                      <DT>
                        <I>City:</I>Harrisburg</DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>State_or_Province:</I>PA</DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Postal_Code:</I>17110-2993</DT>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Voice_Telephone:</I>717-237-2207</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_TDD/TTY_Telephone:</I>800-877-8339</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Facsimile_Telephone:</I>717-237-2238</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Electronic_Mail_Address:</I>joseph.kraft@pa.usda.gov</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
        </DL>
      </DD>
    </DL>
    <A HREF="#Top">Back to Top</A>
    <A name="Data_Quality_Information">
      <HR>
    </A>
    <DL>
      <DT>
        <I>Data_Quality_Information:</I>
      </DT>
      <DD>
        <DL>
          <DT>
            <I>Attribute_Accuracy:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DIV>
                <DT>
                  <I>Attribute_Accuracy_Report:</I>
                </DT>
                <PRE>
Attribute accuracy is tested by manual
comparison of the source with hard copy plots and/or symbolized
display of the map data on an interactive computer graphic system.
Selected attributes that cannot be visually verified on plots or
on screen are interactively queried and verified on screen. In
addition, the attributes are tested against a master set of valid
attributes. All attribute data conform to the attribute codes in
the signed classification and correlation document and amendment(s).
</PRE>
              </DIV>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DIV>
            <DT>
              <I>Logical_Consistency_Report:</I>
            </DT>
            <PRE>
Certain node/geometry and topology GT- polygon/chain relationships
are collected or generated to satisfy topological requirements
(the GT-polygon corresponds to the soil delineation). Some of these
requirements include: chains must begin and end at nodes, chains
must connect to each other at nodes, chains do not extend through
nodes, left and right GT-polygons are defined for each chain
element and are consistent throughout, and the chains representing
the limits of the file are free of gaps. The tests of logical
consistency are performed using vendor software. All internal
polygons are tested for closure with vendor software and are checked
on hard copy plots. All data are checked for common soil lines (i.e.,
adjacent polygons with the same label). Edge locations generally do
not deviate from centerline to centerline by more than 0.01 inch.
The Soil Survey of Adams County, Pennsylvania is edgematched to the
adjacent SSURGO certified Pennsylvania Soil Surveys of York County
and Franklin County and the adjacent SSURGO certified Maryland Soil
Surveys of Carroll County and Frederick County. Feature edges and
descriptive attributes of this soil survey are matched to those in
Franklin and York Counties. Soil delineations are matched to those
in Carroll County, Maryland, but do not match descriptive attributes
exactly. Feature labels do not match adjacent soil surveys exactly.
The soil survey area boundaries match.
</PRE>
          </DIV>
          <DIV>
            <DT>
              <I>Completeness_Report:</I>
            </DT>
            <PRE>
A map unit is a collection of areas defined and named in terms of
their soil components or miscellaneous areas or both. Each map
unit differs in some respect from all others in a survey area and
each map unit has a symbol that uniquely identifies the map unit
on a soil map. Each individual area, point, or line so identified
on the map is a delineation.

Soil Scientists identify small areas of soils or miscellaneous areas
that have properties and behavior significantly different than the
named soils in the surrounding map unit. These minor components
may be indicated as special features. If they have a minimal effect
on use and management, or could not be precisely located, they may
not be indicated on the map.

A map unit has specified kinds of soils or miscellaneous areas
(map unit components), each with a designated range in
proportionate extent. Map units include one or more kinds of soil
or miscellaneous area. Miscellaneous areas are areas that have little
or no recognizable soil.

Specific National Cooperative Soil Survey standards and procedures
were used in the classification of soils, design and name of map
units, and location of special soil features. These standards are
outlined in Agricultural Handbook 18, Soil Survey Manual, 1993,
USDA, NRCS; Agricultural Handbook 436, Soil Taxonomy, 1995,
USDA, NRCS; and all Amendments; Keys to Soil Taxonomy,
(current issue) USDA, NRCS; National Soil Survey
Handbook, title 430-VI,(current issue) USDA, NRCS.

The actual composition and interpretive purity of the map unit
delineations were based on data collected by scientists during
the course of preparing the soil maps. Adherence to National
Cooperative Soil Survey standards and procedures is based on
peer review, quality control, and quality assurance. Quality
control is outlined in the memorandum of understanding for the
soil survey area and in documents that reside with the Natural
Resources Conservation Service state soil scientist. Four kinds
of map units are used in soil surveys: consociations, complexes,
associations, and undifferentiated groups.

Consociations - Consociations are named for the dominant soil.
In a consociation, delineated areas use a single name from the
dominant component in the map unit. Dissimilar components are
minor in extent. The soil component in a consociation may be
identified at any taxonomic level. Soil series is the lowest
taxonomic level. A consociation that is named as a miscellaneous
area is dominantly that kind of area and minor components do not
significantly affect the use of the map unit. The total amount of
dissimilar inclusions of other components in a map unit generally
does not exceed about 15 percent if limiting and 25 percent if
nonlimiting. A single component of a dissimilar limiting inclusion
generally does not exceed 10 percent if very contrasting.

Complexes and associations - Complexes and associations consist
of two or more  dissimilar components that occur in a regularly
repeating pattern. The total amount of other dissimilar components
is minor extent. The following arbitrary rule determines whether
complex or association is used in the name. The major components
of an association can be separated at the scale of mapping. In
either case, because the major components are sufficiently different
in morphology or behavior, the map unit cannot be called a
consociation. In each delineation of a complex or an association,
each major component is normally present though their proportions
may vary appreciably from one delineation to another. The total
amount of inclusions in a map unit that are dissimilar to any of
the major components does not exceed 15 percent if limiting and
25 percent if nonlimiting. A single kind of dissimilar limiting
inclusion usually does not exceed 10 percent.

Undifferentiated groups - Undifferentiated groups consist of two
or more components that are not consistently associated
geographically and, therefore, do not always occur together in
the same map delineation. These components are included in the
same named map unit because their use and management are the same
or very similar for common uses. Generally they are grouped together
because some common feature, such as steepness, stoniness, or
flooding, determines their use and management. If two or more
additional map units would serve no useful purpose, they may be
included in the same unit. Each delineation has at least one of the
major components, and some may have all of them. The same principles
regarding the proportion of minor components that apply to
consociations also apply to undifferentiated groups. The same
principles regarding proportion of inclusion apply to
undifferentiated groups as to consociations.

Minimum documentation consists of three complete soil profile
descriptions that are collected for each soil added to the legend,
one additional per 3,000 acres mapped; three 10 observation
transects for each map unit, one additional 10 point transect per
3,000 acres.

A defined standard or level of confidence in the interpretive
purity of the map unit delineations is attained by adjusting the
kind and intensity of field investigations. Field investigations
and data collection are carried out in sufficient detail to name
map units and to identify accurately and consistently areas of
about 5 acres.
</PRE>
          </DIV>
          <DT>
            <I>Positional_Accuracy:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Horizontal_Positional_Accuracy:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Horizontal_Positional_Accuracy_Report:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
The accuracy of these digital data is based upon their
compilation to base maps that meet National Map
Accuracy Standards at a scale of 1 inch equals 1,000
feet. The difference in positional accuracy between the
soil boundaries and special soil features locations in the
field and their digitized map locations is unknown. The
locational accuracy of soil delineations on the ground varies
with the transition between map units.

For example, on long gently sloping landscapes the transition
occurs gradually over many feet. Where landscapes change
abruptly from steep to level, the transition will be very
narrow. Soil delineation boundaries and special soil features
generally were digitized within 0.01 inch of their locations on
the digitizing source. The digital map elements are edge matched
between data sets. The data along each quadrangle edge are
matched against the data for the adjacent quadrangle. Edge
locations generally do not deviate from centerline to centerline
by more than 0.01 inch.
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Lineage:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Source_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Citation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Citation_Information:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Originator:</I>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Soil Conservation
Service
</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Publication_Date:</I>1967</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Title:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>Soil Survey of Pennsylvania</DD>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form:</I>atlas</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Publication_Information:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
                            <DL>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Publication_Place:</I>Washington, D.C.</DT>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Publisher:</I>U.S. Goverment Printing Office</DT>
                            </DL>
                          </DD>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Scale_Denominator:</I>15840</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Type_of_Source_Media:</I>paper</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Time_Period_of_Content:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Time_Period_Information:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Single_Date/Time:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
                            <DL>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Calendar_Date:</I>1967</DT>
                            </DL>
                          </DD>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Source_Currentness_Reference:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>publication date</DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>SCS1</DD>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Source_Contribution:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
basic reference material about soils and
landscapes
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Source_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Citation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Citation_Information:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Originator:</I>U.S. Geological Survey</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Publication_Date:</I>1981</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Title:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>multiple analog orthophotographs</DD>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form:</I>remote sensing image</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Publication_Information:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
                            <DL>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Publication_Place:</I>Salt Lake City, Utah</DT>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Publisher:</I>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Agricultural
Stabilization and Conservation Service
</DT>
                            </DL>
                          </DD>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Scale_Denominator:</I>24000</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Type_of_Source_Media:</I>stable-base material</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Time_Period_of_Content:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Time_Period_Information:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Single_Date/Time:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
                            <DL>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Calendar_Date:</I>1989</DT>
                            </DL>
                          </DD>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Source_Currentness_Reference:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>correlation date of update</DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>USGS1</DD>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Source_Contribution:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>base materials for field mapping</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Source_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Citation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Citation_Information:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Originator:</I>U.S. Geological Survey</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Publication_Date:</I>1981</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Title:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>multiple analog orthophotographs</DD>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form:</I>remote sensing image</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Publication_Information:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
                            <DL>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Publication_Place:</I>Menlo Park, California</DT>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Publisher:</I>U.S. Geological Survey</DT>
                            </DL>
                          </DD>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Scale_Denominator:</I>24000</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Type_of_Source_Media:</I>stable-base material</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Time_Period_of_Content:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Time_Period_Information:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Single_Date/Time:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
                            <DL>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Calendar_Date:</I>1989</DT>
                            </DL>
                          </DD>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Source_Currentness_Reference:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>correlation date of update</DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>USGS2</DD>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Source_Contribution:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>one-third quadrangle format compilation base</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Source_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Citation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Citation_Information:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Originator:</I>U.S. Geological Survey</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Publication_Date:</I>1981</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Title:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>multiple 7.5 minute analog orthophotograph quadrangles</DD>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form:</I>remote sensing image</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Publication_Information:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
                            <DL>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Publication_Place:</I>Menlo Park, California</DT>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Publisher:</I>U.S. Geological Survey</DT>
                            </DL>
                          </DD>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Scale_Denominator:</I>24000</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Type_of_Source_Media:</I>stable-base material</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Time_Period_of_Content:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Time_Period_Information:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Single_Date/Time:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
                            <DL>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Calendar_Date:</I>1981</DT>
                            </DL>
                          </DD>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Source_Currentness_Reference:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>publication date</DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>USGS3</DD>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Source_Contribution:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>full quadrangle format compilation base</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Source_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Citation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Citation_Information:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Originator:</I>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service
</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Publication_Date:</I>unpublished material</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Title:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>annotated compilation overlays</DD>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form:</I>map</DT>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Scale_Denominator:</I>24000</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Type_of_Source_Media:</I>stable-base material</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Time_Period_of_Content:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Time_Period_Information:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Single_Date/Time:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
                            <DL>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Calendar_Date:</I>1999</DT>
                            </DL>
                          </DD>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Source_Currentness_Reference:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>date of compilation work</DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NRCS1</DD>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Source_Contribution:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>scanning source</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Source_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Citation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Citation_Information:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Originator:</I>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural
Resources Conservation Service
</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Publication_Date:</I>1999</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Title:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
National Map Unit Interpretation Records (MUIR) database
for Pennsylvania
</DD>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form:</I>tabular digital data</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Publication_Information:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
                            <DL>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Publication_Place:</I>Fort Worth, Texas</DT>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Publisher:</I>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service
</DT>
                            </DL>
                          </DD>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Type_of_Source_Media:</I>online</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Time_Period_of_Content:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Time_Period_Information:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Single_Date/Time:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
                            <DL>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Calendar_Date:</I>1999</DT>
                            </DL>
                          </DD>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Source_Currentness_Reference:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>edit date in the ssarea table</DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NRCS2</DD>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Source_Contribution:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
tabular soil property data linked to
spatial soil data
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Source_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Citation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Citation_Information:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Originator:</I>U.S. Geological Survey</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Publication_Date:</I>1992 - 1996</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Title:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>multiple 7.5 minute digital orthophotographs</DD>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form:</I>remotely sensed image</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Publication_Information:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
                            <DL>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Publication_Place:</I>Reston, Virginia</DT>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Publisher:</I>U.S. Geological Survey</DT>
                            </DL>
                          </DD>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Scale_Denominator:</I>24000</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Type_of_Source_Media:</I>stable-base material</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Time_Period_of_Content:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Time_Period_Information:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Range_of_Dates/Times:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
                            <DL>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Beginning_Date:</I>1992</DT>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Ending_Date:</I>1996</DT>
                            </DL>
                          </DD>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Source_Currentness_Reference:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>publication date</DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>USGS4</DD>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Source_Contribution:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>placement of water and county boundaries</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Source_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Citation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Citation_Information:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Originator:</I>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural
Resources Conservation Service
</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Publication_Date:</I>1999</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Title:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
Soil Survey Geographic (SSURGO) database for
Pennsylvania
</DD>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form:</I>vector digital data</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Publication_Information:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
                            <DL>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Publication_Place:</I>Fort Worth, Texas</DT>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Publisher:</I>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service, National Cartography and Geospatial
Center
</DT>
                            </DL>
                          </DD>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Scale_Denominator:</I>24000</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Type_of_Source_Media:</I>online</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Time_Period_of_Content:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Time_Period_Information:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Single_Date/Time:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
                            <DL>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Calendar_Date:</I>1999</DT>
                            </DL>
                          </DD>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Source_Currentness_Reference:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>date of publication</DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NRCS3</DD>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Source_Contribution:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>source for digital revision</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Source_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Citation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Citation_Information:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Originator:</I>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural
Resources Conservation Service
</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Publication_Date:</I>2003</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Title:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
National Soil Information System (NASIS) database for Pennsylvania
</DD>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form:</I>tabular digital data</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Publication_Information:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
                            <DL>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Publication_Place:</I>Fort Collins, Colorado</DT>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Publisher:</I>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service, Information Technology Center
</DT>
                            </DL>
                          </DD>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Type_of_Source_Media:</I>online</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Time_Period_of_Content:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Time_Period_Information:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Single_Date/Time:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
                            <DL>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Calendar_Date:</I>2003</DT>
                            </DL>
                          </DD>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Source_Currentness_Reference:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>export certification date</DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NRCS4</DD>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Source_Contribution:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
tabular soil property data linked to
spatial soil data
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Source_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Citation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Citation_Information:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Originator:</I>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service
</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Publication_Date:</I>2004</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Title:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>National Soil Information System (NASIS) data base</DD>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form:</I>unknown</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Publication_Information:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
                            <DL>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Publication_Place:</I>Fort Collins, Colorado</DT>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Publisher:</I>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service
</DT>
                            </DL>
                          </DD>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Type_of_Source_Media:</I>database</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Time_Period_of_Content:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Time_Period_Information:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Range_of_Dates/Times:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
                            <DL>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Beginning_Date:</I>2004</DT>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Ending_Date:</I>2004</DT>
                            </DL>
                          </DD>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Source_Currentness_Reference:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>publication date</DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NASIS</DD>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Source_Contribution:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>attribute (tabular) information</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Source_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Citation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Citation_Information:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Originator:</I>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service
</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Publication_Date:</I>unpublished material</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Title:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
ArcGIS geodatabase files for the soil survey of Pennsylvania
</DD>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form:</I>digital vector data</DT>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Scale_Denominator:</I>24000</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Type_of_Source_Media:</I>online</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Time_Period_of_Content:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Time_Period_Information:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Single_Date/Time:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
                            <DL>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Calendar_Date:</I>2010</DT>
                            </DL>
                          </DD>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Source_Currentness_Reference:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>2010</DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NRCS5</DD>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Source_Contribution:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
digital information containing area and special
soil features for evaluation
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Source_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Citation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Citation_Information:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Originator:</I>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service
</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Publication_Date:</I>2010</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Title:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>National Soil Information System (NASIS) database</DD>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form:</I>tabular digital data</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Publication_Information:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
                            <DL>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Publication_Place:</I>Fort Collins, Colorado</DT>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Publisher:</I>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service, Information Technology Center
</DT>
                            </DL>
                          </DD>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Type_of_Source_Media:</I>online</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Time_Period_of_Content:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Time_Period_Information:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Single_Date/Time:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
                            <DL>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Calendar_Date:</I>2010</DT>
                            </DL>
                          </DD>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Source_Currentness_Reference:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>export certification date</DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NRCS6</DD>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Source_Contribution:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
map unit legend used for comparison to spatial
map unit labels
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Source_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Citation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Citation_Information:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Originator:</I>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service
</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Publication_Date:</I>unpublished material</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Title:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>region 3 soils geodatabase</DD>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form:</I>file geodatabase</DT>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Type_of_Source_Media:</I>vector digital data</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Time_Period_of_Content:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Time_Period_Information:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Range_of_Dates/Times:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
                            <DL>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Beginning_Date:</I>2006</DT>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Ending_Date:</I>2012</DT>
                            </DL>
                          </DD>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Source_Currentness_Reference:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>SSURGO publication date</DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NRCS7</DD>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Source_Contribution:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>Source of digital revision</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE></PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>SCS1</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>1984</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
Field work started in 1984.  Field data were collected in the form
of transects to determine mapunit composition.  Type locations for
typifying pedons from the previous survey were located and
reclassified with the new standards.  Boundaries were verified in
the field by traversing and transecting the landscape. Soil
scientists then analyzed soil samples in the laboratory, and ran
statistical methods to classify and develop series and mapping
units.  The classification and map unit names for the soil survey
update were finalized at the final correlation in December of 1989.
The soil boundaries were compiled by the field soil scientist on
one-third orthophotographs at a scale of 1:24,000.  The one-third
orthophotographs were compiled to full 7.5 minute quadrangle
orthophotographs at a scale of 1:24,000.  The soil and special
features were then recompiled onto the 7.5 minute mylar separates.
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>USGS1, USGS2, USGS3</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>1998</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
The annotated compilation overlays were scanned at the Pennsylvania
Map Compilation Center using a DMP strip scanner that scanned at
200 dpi. The raster files of the scanned soil lines were imported
into LTPlus for raster editing, map neatline development, labeling,
edgematching, and vector conversion.  The vector files were then
imported into ARC/INFO version 7.0.4 for final plotting, edit
checks, and error analysis. Some registration errors due to the
strip scanner were corrected using the TRANSFORM command to place
the data in the correct coordinate values.  The tic placement is
within standards; however some compression of soil boundaries
occurred in the southern part of each quadrangle leading to some
offset of soil polygons bodies up to 1/16 of an inch in this area.
The spatial data was then exported to GRASS Version 4.13 as Digital
Line Graphs (DLGs). Special features were digitized in GRASS and
compared against the spatial soil data.  The data were written out
in DLG Optional format from GRASS 4.13 with the v.dlg.out command.
Compilation, digitizing, and quality control were performed by the
soil scientists and cartographic technicians at the Pennsylvania
Natural Resource Conservation Service (NRCS) Map Compilation Center.
The digital maps of the soil lines and the special features were
sent to the Temple Texas Digitizing and Certification Center.
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NRCS1</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>1998</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
The Map Unit Interpretations Record (MUIR) data base was developed
by Natural Resources Conservation soil scientists according to
national standards. The database was downloaded using NASIS 5.0
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NRCS2</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>1999</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE></PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NRCS2</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>1999</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE></PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>USGS4, NRCS3</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>2002</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
The National Soil Information System (NASIS) Database was developed
by the NRCS soil scientists according to national standards. The
soil scientists at the Map Compilation and Digitizing Center
generated the statistics on the map unit acreages in the spatial
data.  The staff checked the map unit symbols in the spatial data
against the correlation document and used the map unit acreages of
the spatial data as a guide to populate the NASIS Database.
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NRCS4</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>2003</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
The MIDU staff imported the DLG-3 Optional format files for the soils
and the special features using the ARC/INFO Version 7.2.1 software.
The quadrangle coverages were processed using the Revised October
1998 SSURGO Evaluation AML programs. These ARC/INFO programs
identified areas within the coverages that needed revision. The data
were edited. The Pennsylvania NRCS soil scientists supplied the
SSURGO downloads from NASIS. The minor codes in the soils coverages
were renamed to link the map units in the spatial data to the NASIS
database. New DLG files were written from the updated coverages
according to SSURGO standards. Upon successful completion of the
SSURGO Evaluation, the DLG files and the SSURGO download were
processed with the modified July 2002 Distribution AML programs
provided by NCGC. The re-certified data were electronically
transferred to NCGC for archival and distribution.
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NRCS3, NRCS4</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>2003</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate, upon completion of data quality verification, determined
that the tabular data should be released for official use. A
selected set of map units and components in the soil survey legend was
copied to a staging database, and rating values for selected
interpretations were generated. The list of selected interpretations is
stored in the database table named sainterp.
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NASIS</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>20040309</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate verified that the labels on the digitized soil map units
link to map units in the tabular database, and certified the joined
data sets for release to the Soil Data Warehouse. A system assigned
version number and date stamp were added and the data were copied to
the data warehouse. The tabular data for the map units and components
were extracted from the data warehouse and reformatted into the soil
data delivery data model, then stored in the Soil Data Mart. The spatial
data were copied to the Soil Data Mart without change.
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NASIS</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>20040309</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate, upon completion of data quality verification, determined
that the tabular data should be released for official use. A
selected set of map units and components in the soil survey legend was
copied to a staging database, and rating values for selected
interpretations were generated. The list of selected interpretations is
stored in the database table named sainterp.
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NASIS</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>20040309</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate verified that the labels on the digitized soil map units
link to map units in the tabular database, and certified the joined
data sets for release to the Soil Data Warehouse. A system assigned
version number and date stamp were added and the data were copied to
the data warehouse. The tabular data for the map units and components
were extracted from the data warehouse and reformatted into the soil
data delivery data model, then stored in the Soil Data Mart. The spatial
data were copied to the Soil Data Mart without change.
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NASIS</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>20040310</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate, upon completion of data quality verification, determined
that the tabular data should be released for official use. A
selected set of map units and components in the soil survey legend was
copied to a staging database, and rating values for selected
interpretations were generated. The list of selected interpretations is
stored in the database table named sainterp.
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NASIS</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>20070411</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate verified that the labels on the digitized soil map units
link to map units in the tabular database, and certified the joined
data sets for release to the Soil Data Warehouse. A system assigned
version number and date stamp were added and the data were copied to
the data warehouse. The tabular data for the map units and components
were extracted from the data warehouse and reformatted into the soil
data delivery data model, then stored in the Soil Data Mart. The spatial
data were copied to the Soil Data Mart without change.
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NASIS</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>20070411</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate, generated new rating values for selected interpretations
using current interpretation rules from the NASIS database.
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NASIS</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>20071214</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate, upon completion of data quality verification, determined
that the tabular data should be released for official use. A
selected set of map units and components in the soil survey legend was
copied to a staging database, and rating values for selected
interpretations were generated. The list of selected interpretations is
stored in the database table named sainterp.
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NASIS</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>20080129</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate verified that the labels on the digitized soil map units
link to map units in the tabular database, and certified the joined
data sets for release to the Soil Data Warehouse. A system assigned
version number and date stamp were added and the data were copied to
the data warehouse. The tabular data for the map units and components
were extracted from the data warehouse and reformatted into the soil
data delivery data model, then stored in the Soil Data Mart. The spatial
data were copied to the Soil Data Mart without change.
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NASIS</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>20080130</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
The tabular data were extracted from the data
mart without change. The spatial data's coordinate system was transformed
to UTM Zone 18, Northern Hemisphere (NAD 83) using ESRI ArcObjects 8.3
"ConvertFeatureClass" and exported to an ESRI shapefile.
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NASIS</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>20100616</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
The survey-wide ArcGIS geodatabase from the online SSURGO data were
imported to ARC/INFO 9.2 by certification staff at the Montana
Digitizing Unit. Evaluation macros of July 2009 were applied to the
data. Map unit labels were compared to an approved map unit legend
from the National Soil Information System data base.  ArcMap was
used to join to adjacent survey boundaries and verify previous
adjacent survey joins. The data were uploaded to the soil data
warehouse staging server. The metadata template was updated for
this posting.
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NRCS5, NRCS6</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>20100802</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate verified that the labels on the digitized soil map units
link to map units in the tabular database, and certified the joined
data sets for release to the Soil Data Warehouse. A system assigned
version number and date stamp were added and the data were copied to
the data warehouse. The tabular data for the map units and components
were extracted from the data warehouse and reformatted into the soil
data delivery data model, then stored in the Soil Data Mart. The spatial
data were copied to the Soil Data Mart without change.
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NASIS</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>20100809</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE></PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NRCS7</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>2013</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate, upon completion of data quality verification, determined
that the tabular data should be released for official use. A
selected set of map units and components in the soil survey legend was
copied to a staging database, and rating values for selected
interpretations were generated. The list of selected interpretations is
stored in the database table named sainterp.
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NASIS</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>20131211</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate verified that the labels on the digitized soil map units
link to map units in the tabular database, and certified the joined
data sets for release to the Soil Data Warehouse. A system assigned
version number and date stamp were added and the data were copied to
the data warehouse. The tabular data for the map units and components
were extracted from the data warehouse and reformatted into the soil
data delivery data model, then stored in the Soil Data Mart. The spatial
data were copied to the Soil Data Mart without change.
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NASIS</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>20131211</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate, upon completion of data quality verification, determined
that the tabular data should be released for official use. A
selected set of map units and components in the soil survey legend was
copied to a staging database, and rating values for selected
interpretations were generated. The list of selected interpretations is
stored in the database table named sainterp.
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NASIS</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>20131211</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate verified that the labels on the digitized soil map units
link to map units in the tabular database, and certified the joined
data sets for release to the Soil Data Warehouse. A system assigned
version number and date stamp were added and the data were copied to
the data warehouse. The tabular data for the map units and components
were extracted from the data warehouse and reformatted into the soil
data delivery data model, then stored in the Soil Data Mart. The spatial
data were copied to the Soil Data Mart without change.
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NASIS</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>20131211</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate, upon completion of data quality verification, determined
that the tabular data should be released for official use. A
selected set of map units and components in the soil survey legend was
copied to a staging database, and rating values for selected
interpretations were generated. The list of selected interpretations is
stored in the database table named sainterp.
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NASIS</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>20131213</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate verified that the labels on the digitized soil map units
link to map units in the tabular database, and certified the joined
data sets for release to the Soil Data Warehouse. A system assigned
version number and date stamp were added and the data were copied to
the data warehouse. The tabular data for the map units and components
were extracted from the data warehouse and reformatted into the soil
data delivery data model, then stored in the Soil Data Mart. The spatial
data were copied to the Soil Data Mart without change.
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NASIS</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>20131213</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate, upon completion of data quality verification, determined
that the tabular data should be released for official use. A
selected set of map units and components in the soil survey legend was
copied to a staging database, and rating values for selected
interpretations were generated. The list of selected interpretations is
stored in the database table named sainterp.
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NASIS</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>20140915</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate verified that the labels on the digitized soil map units
link to map units in the tabular database, and certified the joined
data sets for release to the Soil Data Warehouse. A system assigned
version number and date stamp were added and the data were copied to
the data warehouse. The tabular data for the map units and components
were extracted from the data warehouse and reformatted into the soil
data delivery data model, then stored in the Soil Data Mart. The spatial
data were copied to the Soil Data Mart without change.
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>NASIS</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>20140915</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
        </DL>
      </DD>
    </DL>
    <A HREF="#Top">Back to Top</A>
    <A name="Spatial_Data_Organization_Information">
      <HR>
    </A>
    <DL>
      <DT>
        <I>Spatial_Data_Organization_Information:</I>
      </DT>
      <DD>
        <DL>
          <DT>
            <I>Direct_Spatial_Reference_Method:</I>Vector</DT>
        </DL>
      </DD>
    </DL>
    <A HREF="#Top">Back to Top</A>
    <A name="Spatial_Reference_Information">
      <HR>
    </A>
    <DL>
      <DT>
        <I>Spatial_Reference_Information:</I>
      </DT>
      <DD>
        <DL>
          <DT>
            <I>Horizontal_Coordinate_System_Definition:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Geographic:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Latitude_Resolution:</I>0.000001</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Longitude_Resolution:</I>0.0000001</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Geographic_Coordinate_Units:</I>decimal degrees</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Geodetic_Model:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Horizontal_Datum_Name:</I>World Geodetic System 1984</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Ellipsoid_Name:</I>World Geodetic System 1984</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Semi-major_Axis:</I>6378137.00000</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Denominator_of_Flattening_Ratio:</I>298.257222</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
        </DL>
      </DD>
    </DL>
    <A HREF="#Top">Back to Top</A>
    <A name="Entity_and_Attribute_Information">
      <HR>
    </A>
    <DL>
      <DT>
        <I>Entity_and_Attribute_Information:</I>
      </DT>
      <DD>
        <DL>
          <DT>
            <I>Detailed_Description:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Entity_Type:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Entity_Type_Label:</I>Special Soil Features</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Entity_Type_Definition:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
Special Soil Features represent soil, miscellaneous area, or landform
features that are too small to be digitized as soil delineations
(area features).
</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Entity_Type_Definition_Source:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>Agricultural Handbook 18, Soil Survey Manual, 1993, USDA, SCS.</DD>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Attribute:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Attribute_Label:</I>Special Soil Features Codes</DT>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Attribute_Definition:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
Special Soil Features labels represent specific Special Soil
Features. These features are identified with a descriptive
label. The label is assigned to the point or line assigned
to represent the feature on maps.
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Attribute_Definition_Source:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>
Agricultural Handbook 18, Soil Survey Manual, 1993, USDA, SCS;
National Soil Survey Handbook, Title 430-VI, part 647
(current issue), USDA, NRCS.
</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Attribute_Domain_Values:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Codeset_Domain:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Codeset_Name:</I>
Classification and Correlation of the Soils of Pennsylvania SSURGO
</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Codeset_Source:</I>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service
</DT>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Overview_Description:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DIV>
                <DT>
                  <I>Entity_and_Attribute_Overview:</I>
                </DT>
                <PRE>
Map Unit Delineations are closed polygons that may be dominated
by a single soil or miscellaneous area component plus allowable
similar or dissimilar soils, or they can be geographic mixtures
of groups of soils or soils and miscellaneous areas.

The map unit symbol uniquely identifies each closed map unit
delineation. Each symbol corresponds to a map unit name. The
map unit key is used to link to information in the National
Soil Information System tables.

Map Unit Delineations are described by the National Soil
Information System database. This attribute database gives the
proportionate extent of the component soils and the properties for
each soil. The database contains both estimated and measured data
on the physical and chemical soil properties and soil
interpretations for engineering, water management, recreation,
agronomic, woodland, range, and wildlife uses of the soil.

The National Soil Information System database contains static
metadata. It documents the data structure and includes such
information as what tables, columns, indexes, and relationships
are defined as well as a variety of attributes of each of these
database objects. Attributes include table and column
descriptions and detailed domain information.

The National Soil Information System database also contains a
distribution metadata. It records the criteria used for selecting
map units and components for inclusion in the set of distributed
data.

Special features are described in the feature table.  It includes an
area symbol, feature label, feature name, and feature description for
each special and ad hoc feature in the survey area.
</PRE>
              </DIV>
              <DIV>
                <DT>
                  <I>Entity_and_Attribute_Detail_Citation:</I>
                </DT>
                <PRE>
Soil Taxonomy: A basic system of soil classification for making and
interpreting soil surveys. Agricultural Handbook 436, 1999, USDA, SCS.

Keys to Soil Taxonomy (current issue), USDA, SCS.

National Soil Survey Handbook, Title 430-VI, part 647 (current
issue), USDA, NRCS.

Agricultural Handbook 18, Soil Survey Manual, 1993, USDA, SCS.
</PRE>
              </DIV>
            </DL>
          </DD>
        </DL>
      </DD>
    </DL>
    <A HREF="#Top">Back to Top</A>
    <A NAME="EEA">
      <HR>
    </A>
    <DL>
      <DT>
        <I>Distribution_Information:</I>
      </DT>
      <DD>
        <DL>
          <DT>
            <I>Distributor:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Contact_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Organization_Primary:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Contact_Organization:</I>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural
Resources Conservation Service, National
Geospatial Center of Excellence
</DT>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Address:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Address_Type:</I>mailing and physical address</DT>
                      <DIV>
                        <DT>
                          <I>Address:</I>
                        </DT>
                        <PRE>501 West Felix Street, Building 23</PRE>
                      </DIV>
                      <DT>
                        <I>City:</I>Fort Worth</DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>State_or_Province:</I>Texas</DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Postal_Code:</I>76115</DT>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Voice_Telephone:</I>800 672 5559</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_TDD/TTY_Telephone:</I>202 720 2600</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Facsimile_Telephone:</I>817 509 3469</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Resource_Description:</I>Pennsylvania SSURGO SSURGO</DT>
          <DIV>
            <DT>
              <I>Distribution_Liability:</I>
            </DT>
            <PRE>
Although these data have been processed successfully on a computer
system at the U.S. Department of Agriculture, no warranty expressed
or implied is made by the Agency regarding the utility of the data
on any other system, nor shall the act of distribution constitute
any such warranty. The U.S. Department of Agriculture will warrant
the delivery of this product in computer readable format, and will
offer appropriate adjustment of credit when the product is determined
unreadable by correctly adjusted computer input peripherals, or
when the physical medium is delivered in damaged condition. Request
for adjustment of credit must be made within 90 days from the date
of this shipment from the ordering site.

The U.S. Department of Agriculture, nor any of its agencies are
liable for misuse of the data, for damage, for transmission of
viruses, or for computer contamination through the distribution of
these data sets. The U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) prohibits
discrimination in all its programs and activities on the basis of race,
color, national origin, sex, religion, age, disability, political
beliefs, sexual orientation, or marital or family status. (Not all
prohibited bases apply to all programs.)
</PRE>
          </DIV>
          <DT>
            <I>Standard_Order_Process:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Digital_Form:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Digital_Transfer_Information:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Format_Name:</I>ESRI shapefile</DT>
                      <DIV>
                        <DT>
                          <I>Format_Information_Content:</I>
                        </DT>
                        <PRE>spatial</PRE>
                      </DIV>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Transfer_Size:</I>14.2</DT>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Digital_Transfer_Option:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Online_Option:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Computer_Contact_Information:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
                            <DL>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Network_Address:</I>
                              </DT>
                              <DD>
                                <DL>
                                  <DT>
                                    <I>Network_Resource_Name:</I>
                                    <A TARGET="viewer" HREF="URL:http://DataGateway.nrcs.usda.gov/">URL:http://DataGateway.nrcs.usda.gov/</A>
                                  </DT>
                                </DL>
                              </DD>
                            </DL>
                          </DD>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Access_Instructions:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
Select desired survey area at above Internet
Web site. An email address is required for receipt of
instructions on retrieval via anonymous FTP. Anticipate a
delay between submission of request at Web site and receipt of
email message.
</DD>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Fees:</I>
There is currently no direct charge for requesting data or for
retrieval via FTP.
</DT>
              <DIV>
                <DT>
                  <I>Ordering_Instructions:</I>
                </DT>
                <PRE>
Visit the above mentioned Internet Web Site, select state or
territory, then select individual soil survey area of interest.
Spatial line data and locations of special feature symbols are in
ESRI ArcGIS shapefile, format. The National Soil Information
System attribute soil data are available in variable length, pipe
delimited, ASCII file format.
</PRE>
              </DIV>
              <DT>
                <I>Turnaround:</I>Typically within four hours</DT>
            </DL>
          </DD>
        </DL>
      </DD>
    </DL>
    <A HREF="#Top">Back to Top</A>
    <A name="Metadata_Reference_Information">
      <HR>
    </A>
    <DL>
      <DT>
        <I>Metadata_Reference_Information:</I>
      </DT>
      <DD>
        <DL>
          <DT>
            <I>Metadata_Date:</I>20141002</DT>
          <DT>
            <I>Metadata_Contact:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Contact_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Organization_Primary:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Contact_Organization:</I>U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation Service</DT>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Position:</I>State Soil Scientist</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Address:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Address_Type:</I>mailing address</DT>
                      <DIV>
                        <DT>
                          <I>Address:</I>
                        </DT>
                        <PRE>USDA-NRCS</PRE>
                      </DIV>
                      <DIV>
                        <DT>
                          <I>Address:</I>
                        </DT>
                        <PRE>One Credit Union Place, Suite 340</PRE>
                      </DIV>
                      <DT>
                        <I>City:</I>Harrisburg</DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>State_or_Province:</I>PA</DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Postal_Code:</I>17110-2993</DT>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Voice_Telephone:</I>717-237-2207</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_TDD/TTY_Telephone:</I>800-877-8339</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Facsimile_Telephone:</I>717-237-2238</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Electronic_Mail_Address:</I>joseph.kraft@pa.usda.gov</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Metadata_Standard_Name:</I>Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</DT>
          <DT>
            <I>Metadata_Standard_Version:</I>FGDC-STD-001-1998</DT>
        </DL>
      </DD>
    </DL>
    <A HREF="#Top">Back to Top</A>
  </BODY>
</HTML>
		</form>
	</body>
</HTML>
