
<!DOCTYPE HTML PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN">
<HTML>
	<HEAD>
		<title>Pennsylvania Spatial Data Access | Full Metadata</title>
		<meta name="GENERATOR" content="Microsoft Visual Studio.NET 7.0">
		<meta name="CODE_LANGUAGE" content="Visual Basic 7.0">
		<meta name="vs_defaultClientScript" content="JavaScript">
		<meta name="vs_targetSchema" content="http://schemas.microsoft.com/intellisense/ie5">
	    <link rel="shortcut icon" href="http://maps.pasda.psu.edu/Images/favicon.ico" type="image/x-icon" />
        <script>
          (function(i,s,o,g,r,a,m){i['GoogleAnalyticsObject']=r;i[r]=i[r]||function(){
          (i[r].q=i[r].q||[]).push(arguments)},i[r].l=1*new Date();a=s.createElement(o),
          m=s.getElementsByTagName(o)[0];a.async=1;a.src=g;m.parentNode.insertBefore(a,m)
          })(window,document,'script','//www.google-analytics.com/analytics.js','ga');

          ga('create', 'UA-41373351-5', 'psu.edu');
          ga('send', 'pageview');

        </script>
</HEAD>
	<body MS_POSITIONING="GridLayout">
		<form method="post" action="./FullMetadataDisplay.aspx?file=pabba1994.xml" id="Form1">
<input type="hidden" name="__VIEWSTATE" id="__VIEWSTATE" value="/wEPDwULLTEzNDA3MDMyNjVkZCi1cbXMhfZI+elmwl4oTersdOt9nxHHv5HGNLdvg2y4" />

<input type="hidden" name="__VIEWSTATEGENERATOR" id="__VIEWSTATEGENERATOR" value="D999016F" />
			<HTML>
  <HEAD>
    <META http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html; charset=utf-8">
    <SCRIPT type="text/javascript">

      function fix(e) {
        var par = e.parentNode;
        e.id = "";
        e.style.marginLeft = "0.42in";
        var pos = e.innerText.indexOf("\n");
        if (pos > 0) {
          while (pos > 0) {
            var t = e.childNodes(0);
            var n = document.createElement("PRE");
            var s = t.splitText(pos);
            e.insertAdjacentElement("afterEnd", n);
            n.appendChild(s);
            n.style.marginLeft = "0.42in";
            e = n;
            pos = e.innerText.indexOf("\n");
          }
          var count = (par.children.length);
          for (var i = 0; i < count; i++) {
            e = par.children(i);
            if (e.tagName == "PRE") {
              pos = e.innerText.indexOf(">");
              if (pos != 0) {
                n = document.createElement("DD");
                e.insertAdjacentElement("afterEnd", n);
                n.innerText = e.innerText;
                e.removeNode(true);
              }
            }
          }
          if (par.children.tags("PRE").length > 0) {
            count = (par.children.length);
            for (i = 0; i < count; i++) {
              e = par.children(i);
              if (e.tagName == "PRE") {
                e.id = "";
                if (i < (count-1)) {
                  var e2 = par.children(i + 1);
                  if (e2.tagName == "PRE") {
                    e.insertAdjacentText("beforeEnd", e2.innerText+"\n");
                    e2.removeNode(true);
                    count = count-1;
                    i = i-1;
                  }
                }
              }
            }
          }
        }
        else {
          n = document.createElement("DD");
          par.appendChild(n);
          n.innerText = e.innerText;
          e.removeNode(true);
        }
      }

    </SCRIPT>
  </HEAD>
  <BODY oncontextmenu="return true">
    <A name="Top">
    </A>
    <H2>Pennsylvania Breeding Bird Atlas</H2>
    <UL>
      <LI>
        <A HREF="#Identification_Information">Identification_Information</A>
      </LI>
      <LI>
        <A HREF="#Data_Quality_Information">Data_Quality_Information</A>
      </LI>
      <LI>
        <A HREF="#Spatial_Data_Organization_Information">Spatial_Data_Organization_Information</A>
      </LI>
      <LI>
        <A HREF="#Spatial_Reference_Information">Spatial_Reference_Information</A>
      </LI>
      <LI>
        <A HREF="#Entity_and_Attribute_Information">Entity_and_Attribute_Information</A>
      </LI>
      <LI>
        <A HREF="#EHA">
                  Distribution_Information 
                </A>
      </LI>
      <LI>
        <A HREF="#Metadata_Reference_Information">Metadata_Reference_Information</A>
      </LI>
    </UL>
    <A name="Identification_Information">
      <HR>
    </A>
    <DL>
      <DT>
        <I>Identification_Information:</I>
      </DT>
      <DD>
        <DL>
          <DT>
            <I>Citation:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Citation_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Originator:</I>Daniel W. Brauning and F. B. Gill</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Publication_Date:</I>1994</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Title:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>Pennsylvania Breeding Bird Atlas</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form:</I>vector digital data</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Publication_Information:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Publication_Place:</I>Montgomery, Pennsylvania</DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Publisher:</I>The Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia, Pennsylvania Game Commission, and Wild Resource Conservation Fund, Harrisburg, PA</DT>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Online_Linkage:</I>
                    <A TARGET="viewer" HREF="http://www.pasda.psu.edu/">http://www.pasda.psu.edu/</A>
                  </DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Description:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DIV>
                <DT>
                  <I>Abstract:</I>
                </DT>
                <PRE>Part of the Pennsylvania Gap Analysis Project the Breeding Bird Atlas database indicates bird species and nesting behavior of known birds species in Pennsylvania. The database is organized into two primary segments; the block and the species lists (data). Blocks are defined by a code for the USGS topographic map, and the block number. All records are organized by the Atlas region. Various attributes of the Atlas block are incorporated, including geographic features (physiographic locations), effort (hours of fieldwork). The species segment, being replicated the full 320,000 times, was kept to a minimal size, and lists only the species and breeding code, the year and comment. Evidence of birds nesting within an Atlas block was recorded with a set of codes that describe behavior and physical evidence of nesting. These codes are divided into four hierarchical categories, three of which indicate breeding. "Observed," "Possible," "Probable," and "Confirmed" breeding codes represent increasing evidence that nesting occurred within the block a species was recorded. "Probable" and "Confirmed" categories were further segregated into hierarchical codes that represent individual breeding behaviors or physical evidence of nesting. A description of breeding codes may be provided upon request. All of Pennsylvania's 4,928 atlas "blocks" were surveyed, with an average of 65 species per block recorded. A total of 188 breeding species were documented statewide. Data catalogued geographically by atlas "block," USGS 7.5 minute quadrangle, county, and physiographic province. Species files include political status designation and a number of life-history characteristics.</PRE>
              </DIV>
              <DIV>
                <DT>
                  <I>Purpose:</I>
                </DT>
                <PRE>The Pennsylvania Breeding Bird Atlas Project was a cooperative, volunteer-based survey conducted from 1983 through 1989. As part of the Gap Project, the Atlas provides the most comprehensive survey of nesting birds in Pennsylvania's history. Based at the United States Fish and Wildlife Service Cooperative Research Unit at the Pennsylvania State University, the mission of the Gap Project is to identify "gaps" in the protection of biologically rich areas of the commonwealth.</PRE>
              </DIV>
              <DIV>
                <DT>
                  <I>Supplemental_Information:</I>
                </DT>
                <PRE>For information about this dataset see the 'Point of Contact' fields below. For more information about the Breeding Bird Atlas as a whole contact: Daniel W. Brauning, Wildlife Biologist, Pennsylvania Game Commission, 61 Windy Lane, Montgomery, PA 17752 (brauning@state.pa.us). Note: When the Breeding Bird Atlas Database is downloaded from the PASDA website, the links which connect the supporting dBase files to the ArcView shapefile will be lost. In order to use the Atlas, you must first re-establish the necessary links in your ArcView project. Bba.dbf (destination/active table) is linked (i.e. one-to-many and/or one-to-one) to Bbadat.dbf (source table) and Bbaocc.dbf (source table) via "BLOCK_ID". Bbaname.dbf is joined (i.e. many-to-one) to Bbadat.dbf via "SP_CODE". If you have problems re-establishing these links/joins in the ArcView TABLES module, or are unfamiliar with the process, first consult the HELP menu in ArcView by entering "link tables" and "join tables" in the INDEX (i.e. keyword search) menu. (The ESRI/ArcView instructions are very clear!) If you have further questions, contact PASDA at pasda@psu.edu.</PRE>
              </DIV>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Time_Period_of_Content:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Time_Period_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Range_of_Dates/Times:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Beginning_Date:</I>1983</DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Ending_Date:</I>1989</DT>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DIV>
                <DT>
                  <I>Currentness_Reference:</I>
                </DT>
                <PRE>ground condition</PRE>
              </DIV>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Status:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Progress:</I>Complete</DT>
              <DT>
                <I>Maintenance_and_Update_Frequency:</I>Unknown</DT>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Spatial_Domain:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Bounding_Coordinates:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>West_Bounding_Coordinate:</I>-80.5181</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>East_Bounding_Coordinate:</I>-74.617</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>North_Bounding_Coordinate:</I>42.234</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>South_Bounding_Coordinate:</I>39.693</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Keywords:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Theme:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Theme_Keyword_Thesaurus:</I>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Theme_Keyword:</I>breeding bird atlas</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Theme_Keyword:</I>bird</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Theme_Keyword:</I>birds</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Theme_Keyword:</I>aves</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Theme_Keyword:</I>nesting</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Theme_Keyword:</I>survey</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Theme_Keyword:</I>habitat</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Theme_Keyword:</I>biota</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Theme_Keyword:</I>environment</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Place:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Place_Keyword:</I>United States Geological Survey 7.5-minute quadrangles</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Place_Keyword:</I>Pennsylvania</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Access_Constraints:</I>The Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia (ANSP) and the Pennsylvania Game Commission (PGC) reserve the right to deny requests for large portions of Atlas data or request reimbursement for handling costs.</DT>
          <DIV>
            <DT>
              <I>Use_Constraints:</I>
            </DT>
            <PRE>Any use of these data should be accompanied by the following, official, citation. Brauning, D.W. and F.B. Gill. 1983-1989. Pennsylvania Breeding Bird Atlas data. The Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia, Pennsylvania Game Commission, and Wild Resource Conservation Fund, Harrisburg, PA. The ANSP, PGC, and Wild Resource Conservation Fund reserve the right to use Atlas data for research and publication. Raw data or data summaries will be made available for analysis and publication within the constraints of the University of Pittsburgh Press copyright. All three sponsoring institutions must be given credit in any publications incorporating the data. Daniel Brauning must be offered co-authorship for any publication involving substantial portions of the Atlas data. The University of Pittsburgh Press holds copyright to the published Atlas of the Breeding Birds in Pennsylvania and any use of its contents, particularly species distribution maps, must be approved by them.</PRE>
          </DIV>
          <DT>
            <I>Point_of_Contact:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Contact_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Person_Primary:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Contact_Person:</I>Joseph A. Bishop</DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Contact_Organization:</I>Penn State Institutes of the Environmnet </DT>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Address:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Address_Type:</I>mailing address</DT>
                      <DIV>
                        <DT>
                          <I>Address:</I>
                        </DT>
                        <PRE>Land and Water Building</PRE>
                      </DIV>
                      <DT>
                        <I>City:</I>University Park</DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>State_or_Province:</I>Pennsylvania </DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Postal_Code:</I>16802</DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Country:</I>United States</DT>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Voice_Telephone:</I>814-863-0291</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Electronic_Mail_Address:</I>jab190@psu.edu</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Native_Data_Set_Environment:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 2; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.0.0.535</DD>
        </DL>
      </DD>
    </DL>
    <A HREF="#Top">Back to Top</A>
    <A name="Data_Quality_Information">
      <HR>
    </A>
    <DL>
      <DT>
        <I>Data_Quality_Information:</I>
      </DT>
      <DD>
        <DL>
          <DT>
            <I>Attribute_Accuracy:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DIV>
                <DT>
                  <I>Attribute_Accuracy_Report:</I>
                </DT>
                <PRE>All attribute data (e.g. species, breeding status, survey hours) have been manually inspected for spatial and content (i.e. typos) accuracy. Inspections were performed by running the Breeding Bird Atlas Database and comparing results with the original, bound/hardcopy Atlas.</PRE>
              </DIV>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DIV>
            <DT>
              <I>Logical_Consistency_Report:</I>
            </DT>
            <PRE>Each of the 4928 Atlas sample blocks are represented as individual grid cells, and are therefore not subject to logical consistency errors such as overshoots, dangling nodes, duplicate arcs, etc. Coordinate accuracy was tested by overlaying the Atlas sample blocks with the complete set of Pennsylvania 7.5-minute quadrangles; all Atlas sample blocks fit precisely within their parent quadrangles.</PRE>
          </DIV>
          <DIV>
            <DT>
              <I>Completeness_Report:</I>
            </DT>
            <PRE>The integrity of geo-referenced data within the Breeding Bird Atlas Database was verified by running the Atlas and comparing results with the original, bound/hardcopy atlas. Users of the Atlas should note that the supporting dBase files contain accessory data, particularly Bbaname.dbf, which features several items (e.g. "AOU_NUM") that are not essential for the Atlas to function properly. These data appeared in the original Breeding Bird Atlas (non-electronic form), however, and have been preserved here. Note: When the Breeding Bird Atlas Database is downloaded from the PASDA website, the links which connect the supporting dBase files to the ArcView shapefile will be lost. In order to use the Atlas, you must first re-establish the links in your ArcView project. Bba.dbf is linked to Bbadat.dbf and Bbaocc.dbf via "BLOCK_ID". Bbaname.dbf is linked to Bbadat.dbf via "SP_CODE".</PRE>
          </DIV>
          <DT>
            <I>Positional_Accuracy:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Horizontal_Positional_Accuracy:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Horizontal_Positional_Accuracy_Report:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>Horizontal positional accuracy was tested by overlaying the Atlas sample blocks with the complete set of Pennsylvania 7.5-minute quadrangles; all Atlas sample blocks fit precisely within their parent quadrangles.</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Lineage:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Source_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Citation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Citation_Information:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Originator:</I>Daniel W. Brauning</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Publication_Date:</I>1992</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Title:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>Atlas of Breeding Birds in Pennsylvania</DD>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Publication_Information:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
                            <DL>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Publication_Place:</I>Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania</DT>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Publisher:</I>Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania</DT>
                            </DL>
                          </DD>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Scale_Denominator:</I>24000</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Type_of_Source_Media:</I>paper</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>Brauning, D.W. 1992. Atlas of Breeding Birds in Pennsylvania. University of Pittsburgh Press, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.</DD>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Source_Contribution:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>Publication from which spatial and attribute information were extracted.</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Process_Step:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Process_Description:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>To facilitate the incorporation of these data into digital formats, primarily a geographic information system (GIS) format, these data were manipulated in the following manner. 1 - Original, raw, data were formatted and sorted into a DBase IV (.dbf) database management system (DBMS) format. This original file has over 300,000 individual records, one for each species reported within each of the 4928 Atlas sample blocks. The DBase format was selected because it has become an industry standard thus making it easy to import and export files among other digital formats and it is directly used by the GIS software ArcView as its "shapefile" attribute table format. To date we have converted these data between the following software formats: Arc/Info - GIS software (Info DBMS) Microsoft Access - DBMS software Microsoft Excel - Spreadsheet software Lotus 1-2-3 - Spreadsheet software MiniTab - Statistical analysis software Splus - Statistical analysis software 2 - Based on the original Dbase file a second table was created. This table has 4928 records and represents the presence or absence of each of the 211 breeding species recorded within each Atlas block during the survey. The number code representing the breeding status occupies each field. Listed as: (4) confirmed, (3) probable, (2) possible, (1) observed, and (0) absent. 3 - A geographic information system data layer was generated of the Atlas block grid boundaries provided by Daniel Brauning. This layer is provided here in ArcView, shapefile format. 4 - Several fields were added to the original database files. These fields, listed below, were added to provide for analyses and data management to process more efficiently and had no impact on the content and integrity of the original data. Since its official publication there have been no changes or updates made to the original database.</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>Brauning, D.W. 1992. Atlas of Breeding Birds in Pennsylvania. University of Pittsburgh Press, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.</DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Date:</I>19990226</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Process_Contact:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Contact_Information:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>
                        <DL>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Contact_Person_Primary:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
                            <DL>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Contact_Person:</I>Joseph A. Bishop</DT>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Contact_Organization:</I>Penn State Institute fo the Environmnet</DT>
                            </DL>
                          </DD>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Contact_Address:</I>
                          </DT>
                          <DD>
                            <DL>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Address_Type:</I>mailing address</DT>
                              <DIV>
                                <DT>
                                  <I>Address:</I>
                                </DT>
                                <PRE>Land and Water Building</PRE>
                              </DIV>
                              <DT>
                                <I>City:</I>University Park</DT>
                              <DT>
                                <I>State_or_Province:</I>Pennsylvania </DT>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Postal_Code:</I>16802</DT>
                              <DT>
                                <I>Country:</I>United States </DT>
                            </DL>
                          </DD>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Contact_Voice_Telephone:</I>814-863-0291</DT>
                          <DT>
                            <I>Contact_Electronic_Mail_Address:</I>jab190@psu.edu</DT>
                        </DL>
                      </DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
        </DL>
      </DD>
    </DL>
    <A HREF="#Top">Back to Top</A>
    <A name="Spatial_Data_Organization_Information">
      <HR>
    </A>
    <DL>
      <DT>
        <I>Spatial_Data_Organization_Information:</I>
      </DT>
      <DD>
        <DL>
          <DT>
            <I>Indirect_Spatial_Reference_Method:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>The Breeding Bird Atlas includes nesting data on birds throughout the state of Pennsylvania. All of the USGS 7.5-minute quadrangles for Pennsylvania are accounted for. Each of these quads are further subdivided into six sections, for a total of 4928 sample "blocks". NOTE: The GIS component of the Atlas does not consist of "true" Raster data. Rather, the Shapefile has been divided into 4928 blocks, or cells, of equal size.</DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Direct_Spatial_Reference_Method:</I>Raster</DT>
          <DT>
            <I>Raster_Object_Information:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Raster_Object_Type:</I>Grid Cell</DT>
              <DT>
                <I>Row_Count:</I>61</DT>
              <DT>
                <I>Column_Count:</I>94</DT>
            </DL>
          </DD>
        </DL>
      </DD>
    </DL>
    <A HREF="#Top">Back to Top</A>
    <A name="Spatial_Reference_Information">
      <HR>
    </A>
    <DL>
      <DT>
        <I>Spatial_Reference_Information:</I>
      </DT>
      <DD>
        <DL>
          <DT>
            <I>Horizontal_Coordinate_System_Definition:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Geodetic_Model:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Horizontal_Datum_Name:</I>North American Datum of 1927</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Ellipsoid_Name:</I>Clarke 1866</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Semi-major_Axis:</I>6378206.4</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Denominator_of_Flattening_Ratio:</I>294.98</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
        </DL>
      </DD>
    </DL>
    <A HREF="#Top">Back to Top</A>
    <A name="Entity_and_Attribute_Information">
      <HR>
    </A>
    <DL>
      <DT>
        <I>Entity_and_Attribute_Information:</I>
      </DT>
      <DD>
        <DL>
          <DT>
            <I>Detailed_Description:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Entity_Type:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Entity_Type_Label:</I>bba</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Attribute:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Attribute_Label:</I>FID</DT>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Attribute_Definition:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>Internal feature number.</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Attribute_Definition_Source:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>ESRI</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Attribute_Domain_Values:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Unrepresentable_Domain:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Attribute:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Attribute_Label:</I>Shape</DT>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Attribute_Definition:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>Feature geometry.</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Attribute_Definition_Source:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>ESRI</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Attribute_Domain_Values:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Unrepresentable_Domain:</I>
                      </DT>
                      <DD>Coordinates defining the features.</DD>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Attribute:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Attribute_Label:</I>AREA</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Attribute:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Attribute_Label:</I>PERIMETER</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Attribute:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Attribute_Label:</I>BBA_</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Attribute:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Attribute_Label:</I>BBA_ID</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Attribute:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Attribute_Label:</I>NAME</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Attribute:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Attribute_Label:</I>NAME2</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Attribute:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Attribute_Label:</I>BLOCK_ID</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Attribute:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Attribute_Label:</I>QSB_NUM</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Attribute:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Attribute_Label:</I>BLOCK_TYPE</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Attribute:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Attribute_Label:</I>SURVEY_HRS</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Overview_Description:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DIV>
                <DT>
                  <I>Entity_and_Attribute_Overview:</I>
                </DT>
                <PRE>Data are recorded by Atlas "blocks", which are identified by USGS 7.5 minute
topographic maps and named by the topo sheet (as Quad Name on reports) and block number.  A
block is 1/6 of a topo sheer and numbered from the northwest corner (1) to the southeast
corner (6).  A block is 2.5 minutes of latitude by 3.75 minutes of longitude.  The area of a
block is approximately 10 square miles.

Evidence of birds nesting within an Atlas block was recorded with a set of codes that
describe behavior and physical evidence of nesting.  These codes are divided into four
hierarchical categories, three of which indicate breeding.  "Observed," "Possible,"
"Probable," and "Confirmed" breeding codes represent increasing evidence that nesting
occurred within the block a species was recorded.  "Probable" and "Confirmed" categories
were further segregated into hierarchical codes that represent individual breeding behaviors
or physical evidence of nesting.  A description of breeding codes may be provided upon
request.

All of Pennsylvania's 4,928 atlas "blocks" were surveyed, with an average of 65 species per
block recorded.  A total of 188 breeding species were documented statewide.  Data catalogued
geographically by atlas "block," USGS 7.5 minute quadrangle, county, and physiographic
province.  Species files include political status designation and a number of life-history
characteristics.

Note:  When the Breeding Bird Atlas Database is downloaded from the PASDA website, the links
which connect the supporting dBase files to the ArcView shapefile will be lost.  In order to
use the Atlas, you must first re-establish the links in your ArcView project.  Bba.dbf is
linked to Bbadat.dbf and Bbaocc.dbf via "BLOCK_ID".  Bbaname.dbf is linked to Bbadat.dbf via
"SP_CODE".

Disk Contents:  Bba. *** - Three files (.shp, .shx, .dbf) that form the necessary components
of an ArcView GIS shapefile format.  This is the GIS layer of the Breeding Bird Atlas sample
grid.  The 4928 Atlas blocks represent each of the USGS 7.5-minute quadrangle maps that
cover Pennsylvania divided into 6 blocks.  Fields include: Area, Perimeter (Square meters &amp;
meters), Bba_, Bba_id (Two identification fields used internally by the GIS), Name (Eight
character field - first 7 represent the USGS quad name and the last character is the block
number 1-6), Name2 (Place name for each USGS quad map), Block_id (Same as internal code
Bba_id, best used for linking tables within a DBMS structure), Qsb_num (Quad survey block
number, ranges 1-6), Block_type (Three types exist, "B" represents a border block - ie. part
of the block is outside the state boundary, "P" is a priority block ,and " " is a normal
block), Survey_hrs (Reported hours surveyed in each block).

Bbaname.dbf - This file contains identification information for each of the 211 bird species
reported in the Breeding Bird Atlas.  Fields include: Common_nam (common name), Genus,
Species, Old_gname (old genus name), Old_cname (old common name) (The last two fields are
included to address name changes that may have occurred since the bba survey.), Elcode
(element code assigned by The Nature Conservancy), Sp_code, Letcode (Four character code
unique to each species), Aou_Num (American Ornithological Union (AOU) assigned number for
each bird.  The number corresponds closely, but not exactly, to taxonomic order).

Bbaoccur.dbf - This table indicates the presence or absence of each species within each
Atlas sample block.  Fields include: Block-id (Matches IDS with the same field in the GIS
layer), Name (Eight character field - first 7 represent the USGS quad name and the last
character is the block number 1-6), SPxxx (211 fields for each of the Atlas' breeding
species. The xxx matches the numbers listed in the bbaname.dbf table).

Bbadat.dbf  - This table lists all species account records for each species within each
Atlas block.  Over 300,000 records are listed in this file.  Fields include: Quad_num (USGS
7.5-minute quadrangle seven digit identification code), Block_num (Block number in each quad
sheet ranges from 1 to 6), Sp_Code (Same as listed above), Breed-code (Breeding status code.
For details refer to (Brauning 1992)), Year (The year that the highest breeding evidence was
reported for a species in a specific Atlas block), Evidence (Code that represents a
confidence level of each record. Confirmed (4), Probable (3), Possible (2), and Observed (1)
are used), Name (Eight character field - first 7 represent the USGS quad name and the last
character is the block number 1-6), and Block-id.</PRE>
              </DIV>
              <DIV>
                <DT>
                  <I>Entity_and_Attribute_Detail_Citation:</I>
                </DT>
                <PRE>Complete information about the Breeding Bird Atlas Database project for Pennsylvania, including grid block design, breeding codes, volunteer effort, species accounts, and distribution maps, can be found in: Brauning, D.W. 1992. Atlas of Breeding Birds in Pennsylvania. University of Pittsburgh Press, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. While using the digital Breeding Bird Atlas, technical support can be obtained by contacting the Pennsylvania Spatial Data Access system (PASDA) at: pasda@psu.edu.</PRE>
              </DIV>
            </DL>
          </DD>
        </DL>
      </DD>
    </DL>
    <A HREF="#Top">Back to Top</A>
    <A NAME="EHA">
      <HR>
    </A>
    <DL>
      <DT>
        <I>Distribution_Information:</I>
      </DT>
      <DD>
        <DL>
          <DT>
            <I>Distributor:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Contact_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Person_Primary:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Contact_Organization:</I>Pennsylvania Spatial Data Access (PASDA)</DT>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Address:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Address_Type:</I>mailing address</DT>
                      <DIV>
                        <DT>
                          <I>Address:</I>
                        </DT>
                        <PRE>115 Land and Water Building </PRE>
                      </DIV>
                      <DT>
                        <I>City:</I>University Park</DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>State_or_Province:</I>Pennsylvania </DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Postal_Code:</I>16802</DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Country:</I>United States </DT>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Voice_Telephone:</I>(814) 865 - 8792</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Electronic_Mail_Address:</I>pasda@psu.edu</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Resource_Description:</I>Downloadable Data</DT>
          <DT>
            <I>Standard_Order_Process:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Digital_Form:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Digital_Transfer_Information:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Transfer_Size:</I>0.639</DT>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
        </DL>
      </DD>
    </DL>
    <A HREF="#Top">Back to Top</A>
    <A name="Metadata_Reference_Information">
      <HR>
    </A>
    <DL>
      <DT>
        <I>Metadata_Reference_Information:</I>
      </DT>
      <DD>
        <DL>
          <DT>
            <I>Metadata_Date:</I>20100608</DT>
          <DT>
            <I>Metadata_Contact:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Contact_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Organization_Primary:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Contact_Organization:</I>Pennsylvania Spatial Data Access </DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Contact_Person:</I>James Spayd </DT>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Position:</I>Metadata Coordinator</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Address:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Address_Type:</I>REQUIRED: The mailing and/or physical address for the organization or individual.</DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>City:</I>REQUIRED: The city of the address.</DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>State_or_Province:</I>REQUIRED: The state or province of the address.</DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Postal_Code:</I>REQUIRED: The ZIP or other postal code of the address.</DT>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Voice_Telephone:</I>(814) 865 - 8792</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Electronic_Mail_Address:</I>pasda@psu.edu</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Metadata_Standard_Name:</I>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</DT>
          <DT>
            <I>Metadata_Standard_Version:</I>FGDC-STD-001-1998</DT>
          <DT>
            <I>Metadata_Time_Convention:</I>local time</DT>
          <DT>
            <I>Metadata_Extensions:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Online_Linkage:</I>
                <A TARGET="viewer" HREF="http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html">http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</A>
              </DT>
              <DT>
                <I>Profile_Name:</I>ESRI Metadata Profile</DT>
            </DL>
          </DD>
        </DL>
      </DD>
    </DL>
    <A HREF="#Top">Back to Top</A>
  </BODY>
</HTML>
		</form>
	</body>
</HTML>
