
<!DOCTYPE HTML PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN">
<HTML>
	<HEAD>
		<title>Pennsylvania Spatial Data Access | Full Metadata</title>
		<meta name="GENERATOR" content="Microsoft Visual Studio.NET 7.0">
		<meta name="CODE_LANGUAGE" content="Visual Basic 7.0">
		<meta name="vs_defaultClientScript" content="JavaScript">
		<meta name="vs_targetSchema" content="http://schemas.microsoft.com/intellisense/ie5">
	    <link rel="shortcut icon" href="http://maps.pasda.psu.edu/Images/favicon.ico" type="image/x-icon" />
        <script>
          (function(i,s,o,g,r,a,m){i['GoogleAnalyticsObject']=r;i[r]=i[r]||function(){
          (i[r].q=i[r].q||[]).push(arguments)},i[r].l=1*new Date();a=s.createElement(o),
          m=s.getElementsByTagName(o)[0];a.async=1;a.src=g;m.parentNode.insertBefore(a,m)
          })(window,document,'script','//www.google-analytics.com/analytics.js','ga');

          ga('create', 'UA-41373351-5', 'psu.edu');
          ga('send', 'pageview');

        </script>
</HEAD>
	<body MS_POSITIONING="GridLayout">
		<form method="post" action="./FullMetadataDisplay.aspx?file=PABBA_2nd.xml" id="Form1">
<input type="hidden" name="__VIEWSTATE" id="__VIEWSTATE" value="/wEPDwULLTEzNDA3MDMyNjVkZCi1cbXMhfZI+elmwl4oTersdOt9nxHHv5HGNLdvg2y4" />

<input type="hidden" name="__VIEWSTATEGENERATOR" id="__VIEWSTATEGENERATOR" value="D999016F" />
			<HTML>
  <HEAD>
    <META http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html; charset=utf-8">
    <SCRIPT type="text/javascript">

      function fix(e) {
        var par = e.parentNode;
        e.id = "";
        e.style.marginLeft = "0.42in";
        var pos = e.innerText.indexOf("\n");
        if (pos > 0) {
          while (pos > 0) {
            var t = e.childNodes(0);
            var n = document.createElement("PRE");
            var s = t.splitText(pos);
            e.insertAdjacentElement("afterEnd", n);
            n.appendChild(s);
            n.style.marginLeft = "0.42in";
            e = n;
            pos = e.innerText.indexOf("\n");
          }
          var count = (par.children.length);
          for (var i = 0; i < count; i++) {
            e = par.children(i);
            if (e.tagName == "PRE") {
              pos = e.innerText.indexOf(">");
              if (pos != 0) {
                n = document.createElement("DD");
                e.insertAdjacentElement("afterEnd", n);
                n.innerText = e.innerText;
                e.removeNode(true);
              }
            }
          }
          if (par.children.tags("PRE").length > 0) {
            count = (par.children.length);
            for (i = 0; i < count; i++) {
              e = par.children(i);
              if (e.tagName == "PRE") {
                e.id = "";
                if (i < (count-1)) {
                  var e2 = par.children(i + 1);
                  if (e2.tagName == "PRE") {
                    e.insertAdjacentText("beforeEnd", e2.innerText+"\n");
                    e2.removeNode(true);
                    count = count-1;
                    i = i-1;
                  }
                }
              }
            }
          }
        }
        else {
          n = document.createElement("DD");
          par.appendChild(n);
          n.innerText = e.innerText;
          e.removeNode(true);
        }
      }

    </SCRIPT>
  </HEAD>
  <BODY oncontextmenu="return true">
    <A name="Top">
    </A>
    <H2>Second Breeding Bird Atlas </H2>
    <UL>
      <LI>
        <A HREF="#Identification_Information">Identification_Information</A>
      </LI>
      <LI>
        <A HREF="#Data_Quality_Information">Data_Quality_Information</A>
      </LI>
      <LI>
        <A HREF="#Spatial_Data_Organization_Information">Spatial_Data_Organization_Information</A>
      </LI>
      <LI>
        <A HREF="#Spatial_Reference_Information">Spatial_Reference_Information</A>
      </LI>
      <LI>Distribution_Information</LI>
      <LI STYLE="margin-left:0.3in">
        <A HREF="#EHA">
                  Distributor 1</A>
      </LI>
      <LI>
        <A HREF="#EAA">
                  Distribution_Information 
                </A>
      </LI>
      <LI>
        <A HREF="#Metadata_Reference_Information">Metadata_Reference_Information</A>
      </LI>
    </UL>
    <A name="Identification_Information">
      <HR>
    </A>
    <DL>
      <DT>
        <I>Identification_Information:</I>
      </DT>
      <DD>
        <DL>
          <DT>
            <I>Citation:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Citation_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Originator:</I> Pennsylvania Game Commission</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Publication_Date:</I>2016</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Title:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>Second Breeding Bird Atlas </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form:</I>vector digital data</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Publication_Information:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Other_Citation_Details:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>The project was sponsored and published by the Pennsylvania Game Commission, Pennsylvania Society for Ornithology, Carnegie Museum of Natural History, and Audubon Pennsylvania, and these remain the owners of the resulting Dataset.  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Online_Linkage:</I>
                    <A TARGET="viewer" HREF="http://www.pasda.psu.edu/">http://www.pasda.psu.edu/</A>
                  </DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Description:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DIV>
                <DT>
                  <I>Abstract:</I>
                </DT>
                <PRE>Twenty years after the first Atlas of Breeding Birds in Pennsylvania was published, the Second Atlas of Breeding Birds in Pennsylvania brings our knowledge of the state’s bird populations up to date, documenting current distribution and changes in status for nearly two hundred breeding bird species. More than two thousand dedicated birdwatchers completed surveys of birds across the state from 2004 to 2009. The data amassed reveal the distribution of each species and show changes in distribution since the publication of the first Atlas. The core results of the project are the distribution maps. In fact, up to three maps per species show in fine detail the current distribution of all breeding birds based on the second Atlas, changes in distribution since the first Atlas, and, for more than one hundred species, their density across Pennsylvania.The field project was based at Powdermill Nature Reserve, environmental research center of the Carnegie Museum of Natural History, in Rector, Pennsylvania. Bob Mulvihill and Mike Lanzone were project co-coordinators. Following the recommendations of the North American Ornithological Atlas Committee, the basic survey unit was the “block,” defined as one-sixth of a standard U.S. Geological Survey 7.5-minute topographic map, of which 4,937 were identified for survey coverage. Local coordination was provided by volunteer Regional Coordinators, who provided the foundation for organizing fieldwork. Eventually, 83 individuals served as Regional Coordinators (see the list under the Credits tab).Breeding bird atlases employ a set of codes to record the behaviors associated with nesting activity, ranging from the simplest detection by sight or sound, through confirmation of active nests and fledged young. Birds observed in breeding habitat, and within their particular breeding season, were placed in one of four categories based on breeding evidence — observations outside breeding habitat, or Possible, Probable, or Confirmed breeding — with a two-letter code used for confirmed breeding evidence and single letter codes for all other categories (See Project Methods – Breeding Codes). The second Atlas did not recommend undue effort to confirm breeding of common species, because it was believed that the field time could be better spent compiling species lists from multiple blocks. Obtaining confirmed breeding evidence was stressed for species identified in a particular conservation or priority category or for species simply rare or unexpected within the block.</PRE>
              </DIV>
              <DIV>
                <DT>
                  <I>Purpose:</I>
                </DT>
                <PRE>The Pennsylvania Breeding Bird Atlas Project is a field project designed to map the distribution of all bird species in a region during a particular time period. Atlases bring together volunteer bird watchers, working as citizen scientists, and professional ornithologists into an effort of monumental proportions, providing great conservation benefits and personal satisfaction.</PRE>
              </DIV>
              <DIV>
                <DT>
                  <I>Supplemental_Information:</I>
                </DT>
                <PRE>Owners grant users a non-exclusive, non-transferable, non-assignable, non-sub-licensable license (the “License”) to use the Dataset for analyses by the User as it may be applicable to the User’s operations or land. Nothing in this Agreement gives User any right, title or interest in the Dataset, other than the License rights granted. The User recognizes and acknowledges ownership of Dataset by the Owner, and agrees not to use, nor directly or indirectly permit the use of, the Dataset in any manner not expressly permitted by this License without the prior written consent of the Owner.</PRE>
              </DIV>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Time_Period_of_Content:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Time_Period_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Range_of_Dates/Times:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Beginning_Date:</I>2004</DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Ending_Date:</I>2009</DT>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DIV>
                <DT>
                  <I>Currentness_Reference:</I>
                </DT>
                <PRE>ground condition</PRE>
              </DIV>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Status:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Progress:</I>Complete</DT>
              <DT>
                <I>Maintenance_and_Update_Frequency:</I>Unknown</DT>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Spatial_Domain:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Bounding_Coordinates:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>West_Bounding_Coordinate:</I>-80.5181</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>East_Bounding_Coordinate:</I>-74.617</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>North_Bounding_Coordinate:</I>42.234</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>South_Bounding_Coordinate:</I>39.693</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Keywords:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Theme:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Theme_Keyword_Thesaurus:</I>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Theme_Keyword:</I>breeding bird atlas</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Theme_Keyword:</I>bird</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Theme_Keyword:</I>birds</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Theme_Keyword:</I>aves</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Theme_Keyword:</I>nesting</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Theme_Keyword:</I>survey</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Theme_Keyword:</I>habitat</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Theme_Keyword:</I>biota</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Theme_Keyword:</I>environment</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Place:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Place_Keyword:</I>United States Geological Survey 7.5-minute quadrangles</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Place_Keyword:</I>Pennsylvania</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Access_Constraints:</I>The Pennsylvania Game Commission   reserve all rights in the Dataset provided. All data in the Dataset are provided as is. This is not a survey quality Dataset. The Owners make no warranty as to the currency, completeness, accuracy or utility of any specific data. This disclaimer applies both to individual use of the data and aggregate use with other data. It is strongly recommended that careful attention be paid to the contents of the metadata file associated with the Dataset.</DT>
          <DIV>
            <DT>
              <I>Use_Constraints:</I>
            </DT>
            <PRE>The Pennsylvania Game Commission shall not be held liable for improper or incorrect use of the Dataset described and/or contained herein, and are indemnified and held harmless from any and all claims, liability, damages, injuries, and suits arising from the use of the Dataset.  Any sale, distribution, loan, transfer, assignment, or offering for use of the Dataset, in whole or in part, is prohibited without the prior written approval of the Nature Conservancy and Western Pennsylvania Conservancy. The use of these data to produce other GIS products and services with the intent to sell for a profit is prohibited without the written consent of The Nature Conservancy and Western Pennsylvania Conservancy. All employees and agents of the User receiving these data must be informed of these restrictions.
Any reports, maps, or other products derived from the Dataset shall acknowledge The Pennsylvania Game Commission,  as a data contributor by including the following language: “The Second Atlas of Breeding Birds of Pennsylvania Dataset is owned jointly by The Nature Conservancy and Western Pennsylvania Conservancy. It represents the relative probability of  xxx .”
No Endorsements: The use of this dataset does not constitute endorsement by The Nature Conservancy Distribution liability 
</PRE>
          </DIV>
          <DT>
            <I>Point_of_Contact:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Contact_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Organization_Primary:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Contact_Organization:</I>Pennsylvania Game Commission</DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Contact_Person:</I>?Daniel W. Brauning</DT>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Electronic_Mail_Address:</I>dbrauning@pa.gov	</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
        </DL>
      </DD>
    </DL>
    <A HREF="#Top">Back to Top</A>
    <A name="Data_Quality_Information">
      <HR>
    </A>
    <DL>
      <DT>
        <I>Data_Quality_Information:</I>
      </DT>
      <DD>
        <DL>
          <DT>
            <I>Attribute_Accuracy:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DIV>
                <DT>
                  <I>Attribute_Accuracy_Report:</I>
                </DT>
                <PRE>All attribute data (e.g. species, breeding status, survey hours) have been manually inspected for spatial and content (i.e. typos) accuracy. Inspections were performed by running the Breeding Bird Atlas Database and comparing results with the original, bound/hardcopy Atlas.</PRE>
              </DIV>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DIV>
            <DT>
              <I>Logical_Consistency_Report:</I>
            </DT>
            <PRE>Each of the 4928 Atlas sample blocks are represented as individual grid cells, and are therefore not subject to logical consistency errors such as overshoots, dangling nodes, duplicate arcs, etc. Coordinate accuracy was tested by overlaying the Atlas sample blocks with the complete set of Pennsylvania 7.5-minute quadrangles; all Atlas sample blocks fit precisely within their parent quadrangles.</PRE>
          </DIV>
          <DT>
            <I>Positional_Accuracy:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Horizontal_Positional_Accuracy:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DIV>
                    <DT>
                      <I>Horizontal_Positional_Accuracy_Report:</I>
                    </DT>
                    <PRE>Horizontal positional accuracy was tested by overlaying the Atlas sample blocks with the complete set of Pennsylvania 7.5-minute quadrangles; all Atlas sample blocks fit precisely within their parent quadrangles.</PRE>
                  </DIV>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Lineage:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
            </DL>
          </DD>
        </DL>
      </DD>
    </DL>
    <A HREF="#Top">Back to Top</A>
    <A name="Spatial_Data_Organization_Information">
      <HR>
    </A>
    <DL>
      <DT>
        <I>Spatial_Data_Organization_Information:</I>
      </DT>
      <DD>
        <DL>
        </DL>
      </DD>
    </DL>
    <A HREF="#Top">Back to Top</A>
    <A name="Spatial_Reference_Information">
      <HR>
    </A>
    <DL>
      <DT>
        <I>Spatial_Reference_Information:</I>
      </DT>
      <DD>
        <DL>
          <DT>
            <I>Horizontal_Coordinate_System_Definition:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Geographic:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Latitude_Resolution:</I>8.9831528411952133e-009</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Longitude_Resolution:</I>8.9831528411952133e-009</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Geographic_Coordinate_Units:</I>Decimal Degrees</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
              <DT>
                <I>Geodetic_Model:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Horizontal_Datum_Name:</I>D North American 1983</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Ellipsoid_Name:</I>GRS 1980</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Semi-major_Axis:</I>6378137.0</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Denominator_of_Flattening_Ratio:</I>298.257222101</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
        </DL>
      </DD>
    </DL>
    <A HREF="#Top">Back to Top</A>
    <A NAME="EHA">
      <HR>
    </A>
    <DL>
      <DT>
        <I>Distribution_Information:</I>
      </DT>
      <DD>
        <DL>
          <DT>
            <I>Distributor:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Contact_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Person_Primary:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Contact_Organization:</I>Pennsylvania Spatial Data Access (PASDA)</DT>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Address:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Address_Type:</I>mailing address</DT>
                      <DIV>
                        <DT>
                          <I>Address:</I>
                        </DT>
                        <PRE>115 Land and Water Building </PRE>
                      </DIV>
                      <DT>
                        <I>City:</I>University Park</DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>State_or_Province:</I>Pennsylvania </DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Postal_Code:</I>16802</DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Country:</I>United States </DT>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Voice_Telephone:</I>(814) 865 - 8792</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Electronic_Mail_Address:</I>pasda@psu.edu</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Resource_Description:</I>Downloadable Data</DT>
          <DIV>
            <DT>
              <I>Distribution_Liability:</I>
            </DT>
            <PRE>The USER shall indemnify, save harmless, and, if requested, defend those parties involved with the development and distribution of this data, their officers, agents, and employees from and against any suits, claims, or actions for injury, death, or property damage arising out of the use of or any defect in the FILES or any accompanying documentation. Those parties involved with the development and distribution excluded any and all implied warranties, including warranties or merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose and makes no warranty or representation, either express or implied, with respect to the FILES or accompanying documentation, including its quality, performance, merchantability, or fitness for a particular purpose. The FILES and documentation are provided "as is" and the USER assumes the entire risk as to its quality and performance. Those parties involved with the development and distribution of this data will not be liable for any direct, indirect, special, incidental, or consequential damages arising out of the use or inability to use the FILES or any accompanying documentation.</PRE>
          </DIV>
          <DT>
            <I>Standard_Order_Process:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Digital_Form:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Digital_Transfer_Information:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Transfer_Size:</I>0.639</DT>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
        </DL>
      </DD>
    </DL>
    <A HREF="#Top">Back to Top</A>
    <A NAME="EAA">
      <HR>
    </A>
    <DL>
      <DT>
        <I>Distribution_Information:</I>
      </DT>
      <DD>
        <DL>
          <DIV>
            <DT>
              <I>Distribution_Liability:</I>
            </DT>
            <PRE>The Pennsylvania Game Commission and other Owners make no warranty, expressed or implied, as to the use or appropriateness of use of the Dataset, nor are there warranties of merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose or use. No representation is made as to the currency, accuracy or completeness of the Dataset or of the data sources on which it is based. The Nature Conservancy and Western Pennsylvania Conservancy shall not be liable for any lost profits or consequential damages, or claims against the User by third parties.</PRE>
          </DIV>
        </DL>
      </DD>
    </DL>
    <A HREF="#Top">Back to Top</A>
    <A name="Metadata_Reference_Information">
      <HR>
    </A>
    <DL>
      <DT>
        <I>Metadata_Reference_Information:</I>
      </DT>
      <DD>
        <DL>
          <DT>
            <I>Metadata_Date:</I>20100608</DT>
          <DT>
            <I>Metadata_Contact:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Contact_Information:</I>
              </DT>
              <DD>
                <DL>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Organization_Primary:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Contact_Organization:</I>Pennsylvania Spatial Data Access </DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Contact_Person:</I>James Spayd </DT>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Position:</I>Metadata Coordinator</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Address:</I>
                  </DT>
                  <DD>
                    <DL>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Address_Type:</I></DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>City:</I></DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>State_or_Province:</I></DT>
                      <DT>
                        <I>Postal_Code:</I></DT>
                    </DL>
                  </DD>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Voice_Telephone:</I>(814) 865 - 8792</DT>
                  <DT>
                    <I>Contact_Electronic_Mail_Address:</I>pasda@psu.edu</DT>
                </DL>
              </DD>
            </DL>
          </DD>
          <DT>
            <I>Metadata_Standard_Name:</I>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</DT>
          <DT>
            <I>Metadata_Standard_Version:</I>FGDC-STD-001-1998</DT>
          <DT>
            <I>Metadata_Time_Convention:</I>local time</DT>
          <DT>
            <I>Metadata_Extensions:</I>
          </DT>
          <DD>
            <DL>
              <DT>
                <I>Online_Linkage:</I>
                <A TARGET="viewer" HREF="http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html">http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</A>
              </DT>
              <DT>
                <I>Profile_Name:</I>ESRI Metadata Profile</DT>
            </DL>
          </DD>
        </DL>
      </DD>
    </DL>
    <A HREF="#Top">Back to Top</A>
  </BODY>
</HTML>
		</form>
	</body>
</HTML>
